<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English Posts on Hugo-HT</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English Posts on Hugo-HT</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:56:58 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning From Markdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/05/learning-from-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:56:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/05/learning-from-markdown/</guid>
      <description>When I was creating my own website, I learned my very first programming language: Markdown&#xD;.&#xA;The link above is an official guidance for markdown, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t read it entirely because I only focused on the questions I &amp;rsquo;ve met or I would have probably. In fact, most of my knowledge learned from the blog of Hongtao Hao&#xD;who was a student majored in journalism and communication then trasfered to computation science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/05/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 15:44:20 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/07/05/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning from 0 to 1 Machine Learning is the subfield of the artificial interlligence that give computers the ability to learn without being explicityly programmed.1&#xA;The main types of machine learning are supervised learning and unsupervised learning.&#xA;Supervised Learning learns from being given “right ansers” has been used most widely in real-world applications including spam filtering, speech recoginition, machine translation, online adversising, self-driving cars and visual inspection. The two major algorithms in supervised learning are regression and classification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlight of Calculus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/06/25/highlight-of-calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 11:32:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/06/25/highlight-of-calculus/</guid>
      <description>Highlight of Calculus These notes capture the key highlights and concepts from the renowned MIT calculus course taught by Professor Gilbert Strang.&#xA;Overview Calculus deals with the relationships between functions and encompasses both integration and differential calculus. These two types of calculus operate in opposite directions.&#xA;Differential: Suppose we know the distance and time. To determine the speed, we can use differential calculus. Intergration: Integration is in the opposite direction. An example of integration is finding the distance function (function 2) when the speed (function 1) increases at a constant rate.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
